Hello English learners.
Welcome to English Pod.
I'm joined here today with Erica
and my name is Marco and we're
going to be looking at
an office lesson today.
That's right. We've got
a lesson about describing
somebody who's not such
a good employee. Right.
So we're going to be
talking about how to describe
this type of situation and
language for making your point.
Yes. So let's look at some vocabulary
from the dialogue in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview. So
two words today. The first one
is a good fit. A
good fit. A good fit.
A good fit. So when we're
talking about an employee and
he's a good fit, I mean,
he's suitable for the job.
Yes, he's suitable for the
job or for the company.
Or for the company, right?
So the opposite would
be not a good fit.
Exactly. The title of today's
lesson. Right. And our
last word for vocabulary
preview performance
performance performance.
Your performance is how
good or bad you do your job.
Right. So you can have good
performance or bad performance.
Just how well you
do your job. Perfect.
So now we're ready
to listen to our dialogue
for the first time. And
as always, it's going to
be at a normal speed, but
you don't have to worry about it.
Because we'll come back and explain all
the key language. Now we're going to listen
as two managers discuss the
performance of one employee.
So Lauren, I just
wanted to talk to you
quickly about our new customer
support representative Jason Huntley.
Sure. What's up?
Basically, I've got a
few concerns about him.
And the bottom line is I
don't think he's a good fit
for our company. Okay.
What makes you say that?
I thought you were pleased
with his overall performance.
Didn't you just tell me last week how
impressed you were with his attitude?
Yeah, his attitude is great,
but he's really unreliable.
Sometimes he's
really productive,
but then other times take
last Tuesday, for instance,
he was 45 minutes late
for a morning meeting.
Well, I'm sure he had a
perfectly good reason.
But that's not the only thing.
You know, he really doesn't
have the best work ethic.
I'm constantly catching
him on MSN and Facebook
when he should
be talking to clients.
Yeah, but come on, Jeff. As if
you don't check Facebook at work.
Look, you hired this guy.
We've invested a lot of time
and money in his training.
So now it's up to you to coach him.
Make it work, Jeff.
Make it, Jeff. You would say that, wouldn't
you? He is your cousin, when you jerk.
So apparently Lauren
hired her cousin. Yes.
That's always a complicated
situation working with family members.
Yeah, it makes it really difficult for
Jeff, doesn't it? Yeah. And apparently Jeff
isn't very happy. Well,
let's look at the language
he used to tell us that
he's unhappy about this.
Language takeaway.
Okay, the first word on
language takeaway
today, unreliable, unreliable,
unreliable, unreliable.
So let's listen to some
examples of unreliable
so then you can understand
what it means. Example
one. The trains here
are so unreliable. They
never arrive on time.
Example two, Thomas is pretty unreliable.
He never finishes his projects on time.
Example three.
You promised you would pick me up
from work today. You're so unreliable.
We can understand that
if someone is unreliable,
we can't trust them
to do their job, right?
Right. So you don't
want to be unreliable.
The opposite would be reliable,
reliable. You can trust them.
Okay. Our second word today, productive,
productive, productive, productive.
When you're productive, it means
that you accomplish your job, right?
You do a lot of work in
a short amount of time.
Productive. Mm-hmm.
You want to be a
productive employee. Yes.
Our third word, work ethic.
Work ethic. Work ethic.
Work ethic. So a person's
work ethic is that person's
attitude towards work.
Yes. If someone has a
good work ethic, then
they are always hardworking
and they come to work
early and they finish
their jobs on time and they
stay and do lots of
overtime. So that's a good
work ethic. Mm-hmm. Okay.
Great. And our last word,
coach, coach, coach. When
you coach and employee,
you train them, right?
Yeah. You help that employee
out by showing him or
her how to do certain tasks
or how to do their job
better. Right. Mm-hmm.
So we've got some
great language to describe
work performance. Let's listen
to our dialogue a second time.
This time, it'll be a little bit
slower so you can understand these words
and phrases a little bit more clearly.
So, Lauren, I just wanted
to talk to you quickly
about our new customer
support representative,
Jason Huntley. Sure.
What's up? Basically, I've
got a few concerns about
him and the bottom line
is I don't think he's a
good fit for our company.
Okay. What makes you
say that? I thought you
were pleased with his
overall performance.
Didn't you just tell me last
week how impressed you were
with his attitude? Yeah.
His attitude is great,
but he's really
unreliable. Sometimes he's
really productive, but
then other times take last
Tuesday, for instance.
He was 45 minutes late
for our morning meeting.
Well, I'm sure he had
a perfectly good reason.
But that's not the only thing.
You know, he really doesn't have the best
work ethic. I'm constantly catching him on
MSN and Facebook when
he should be talking to clients.
Yeah, but come on,
Jeff. As if you don't
check Facebook at work.
Look, you hired this guy.
We've invested a lot
of time and money in his
training. So now it's
up to you to coach him.
Make it work, Jeff. You
would say that, wouldn't
you? He is your
cousin. What a jerk.
Make me hire your stupid
useless cousin. All right, so if you
noticed a lot of useful
phrases have come up.
So let's take a look
at fluency builder.
Fluency builder today, we
have three phrases. That's right.
Three phrases that will help
us make our point better.
The first one is
bottom line, the bottom
line, the bottom line.
Let's listen to how this
was used in the dialogue.
And the bottom line is
I don't think he's a
good fit for our company.
And the bottom line
is I don't think he's a
good fit for our company.
So basically, it means
like the most important
point, the most important
point, perfect, the bottom
line, our second word,
overall, overall, overall.
So this is the same
as saying on the whole,
right? The big picture,
how you would say,
yeah, in general, in general.
So his overall
performance is good.
I mean, it's in general, his
performance is good. Perfect.
And our last phrase is
very interesting because
we can mix it up a little
bit. Yeah, perfectly good.
Perfectly good. Perfectly
good. Perfectly good.
So this is an interesting
phrase because you
can describe different
objects in this way.
Yeah, a perfectly good reason. A perfectly
good car. A perfectly good computer.
So by the sounds of it,
it's kind of like justifying.
Yeah, it's saying there's
no problem with it.
There's no problem with it. Why would throw
it away if it's a perfectly good computer?
Exactly. Okay, perfectly
good. Okay, so now we can
listen to our dialogue a
third time at a normal speed.
And now we're ready
to understand everything.
So Lauren, I just wanted
to talk to you quickly
about our new customer support
representative, Jason Huntley.
Sure. What's up?
Basically, I've got
a few concerns about
him. And the bottom line is,
I don't think he's a
good fit for our company.
Okay. What makes you
say that? I thought you were
pleased with his
overall performance.
Didn't you just tell me last
week how impressed you were
with his attitude? Yeah,
his attitude is great,
but he's really unreliable.
Sometimes he's really
productive, but then other
times take last Tuesday,
for instance, he was
45 minutes late for our
morning meeting. Well, I'm sure
he had a perfectly good reason.
But that's not the only thing.
You know, he really doesn't
have the best work ethic.
I'm constantly catching him
on MSN and Facebook when
he should be talking to
clients. Yeah, but come
on, Jeff, as if you don't
check Facebook at work,
look, you hired this guy.
We've invested a lot of
time and money in his
training. So now it's up to
you to coach him,
make it work, Jeff.
Make it very Jeff. You would
say that. Wouldn't you? He is
your cousin. I hope everyone
enjoyed our lesson today.
We've found some really useful
vocabulary for a business situation. Yes.
So go to our website at
englishpot.com or you can leave all your
questions and comments and
also find a lot of other resources.
That's right. Marco
and I are always
on the site and we're happy
to answer your questions.
Right. So until
then, it's goodbye.